<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Code with Hugo</title>
    <link>https://codewithhugo.com/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Code with Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codewithhugo.com/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Split an existing git commit</title>
      <link>https://codewithhugo.com/split-an-existing-git-commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codewithhugo.com/split-an-existing-git-commit/</guid>
      <description>One of git&amp;rsquo;s main differences when compared to other version control systems is that it lets the user rewrite the history. The main way to do this is to use git rebase, usually followed by a git push --force to overwrite history the remote with the local history.
Here’s a look at how to split existing commits using rebase, reset and commit.
Say you have two files edited in a commit (A and B) and you would like to get the changes from one of those files (A) into your current branch but not those from the other (B).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn git even if you don’t code</title>
      <link>https://codewithhugo.com/learn-git-even-if-you-dont-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codewithhugo.com/learn-git-even-if-you-dont-code/</guid>
      <description>The tools we wield define us, git is the one tool all developers use Git is a ubiquitous version control tool. The way it works tightly correlates with software engineering and the mindsets of developers. It was purpose-built and designed to be used for the development of the Linux Kernel, one of the largest software projects that’s depended on by millions of developers.
Your editing workflow is painful because it’s not version-controlled As part of a team, your editing workflow probably consists of sending a file back and forth for review, comment and amendments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>